Tiana Silva

International Educator-turned-Coder github.com/t4tiana | Columbus, OH | linkedin.com/in/tianasilva

Summary

Fullstack bootcamp grad who discovered a love for coding after nearly a decade teaching high school Economics and working in diverse teams across Asia and the Middle East. Driven by a commitment to constantly expand knowledge and capabilities.

Skills

Object Oriented Programming: C# .NET, Java, Python

Web Application Development: Spring, ASP.NET, REST APIs, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Vue.js, React.js, SPAs

Database Programming: PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB, E/R diagrams

Development Tools and Techniques: Git, Agile Development, Jira, Confluence, Unit Testing, Integration Testing, Docker, Postman

Projects - available on Github

Medication Tracker Android App (Java, XML, Android Studio)

Aug 2024

 Currently in progress as a means to learn mobile development. Planned MVP features include time-sensitive reminders to take medication, Call Doctor option, and refill notifications in a clean, user-friendly UI optimized for elderly users

Fast and the Furious Film Review Web App (Java, Spring Boot, MongoDB, React)

Jul 2024 - Aug 2024

■ Utilized The Movie Database public API to create a React web app for fans of the film franchise. Users can view movie data and write film reviews which are persisted in a NoSQL database. Mobile-first design accommodates different screen sizes and features embedded movie trailers so video can be played without redirecting, improving UX and reducing bounce rate

Storage Auction Web App (C#, ASP.NET, SQL Server, REST, Vue.js)

Apr 2024 - May 2024

Created user-friendly SPA that allows users to view storage units for auction. Signed-in users can place bids and view bid history, and admin users can edit unit information with data persisted in a T-SQL database. Auction expiration counts down in realtime and automatically sends an e-mail to the winning bidder with details on how to claim unit

Work Experience

Associate Software Engineer

May 2024 - Present

OCLC

- Develop high-quality enterprise software solutions for OCLC's Worldshare Management Systems (WMS) SaaS product using Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, and React leading to successful RFP bids
- Investigate technical issues related to WMS's Acquisitions service using debugging skills and code resolutions at or before expected times listed on Jira, enabling application to resume expected functionality to over 850 client institutions
- Collaborate closely with international, cross-functional agile team of 18 including developers, architects, QA, and product owners to understand client requirements and turn them into technical solutions

Subject Matter Expert (Product)

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

- Strive Math (YC S21)
 - Increased client acquisition from 3 to 9 within four months by capitalizing on knowledge of industry trends and collaborating with co-founders to create go-to-market strategy for new after-school coding program
 - Maintained data in Airtable and wrote JavaScript automations to streamline client interactions and ensure consistent and timely communication with 150+ current and prospective customers
 - Established and nurtured client partnerships, leading to more than 5x increase in student enrollment for company-hosted hackathon within two months of onboarding

High School Economics Teacher and Team Lead

Aug 2016 - Jun 2023

International Schools in Taipei, Dubai, and Singapore

- Promoted to team lead positions in Taipei and Singapore coinciding with periods of curriculum overhaul and implementation of new learning management system. Facilitated change management and met all milestones ahead of project timelines
- Regularly conducted data analysis of over 300 student exams and coordinated adaptation of assessments, resulting in students exceeding target achievement by an average of 12% each year
- Created data visualizations of exam results and periodically delivered findings to senior leadership, securing approval for increased headcount and justifying department budget allocation

Education

.NET/C# Web Application Developer

Jan 2024 - Apr 2024

Tech Elevator

Columbus, OH

Winner: Represent Tech Scholarship. Completed an in-person, full stack coding bootcamp amounting to 800+ hours of coding, learning how to create dynamic web applications using C# and Microsoft development tools

Master of Science, Business and Management

Sep 2020 - Sep 2021

University of Strathclyde

Glasgow, UK

Winner: Best Master's Thesis. Subsequently published in the peer-reviewed International Journal for Knowledge Management

Bachelor of Arts, Political Science

Aug 2009 - May 2013

Chapman University

Orange, CA